<page><title>
Certification
</title>

<p> This site runs on the same mod_virgule engine that powers <a
href="http://www.advogato.org/">Advogato</a>. One of the more
interesting features of Advogato is its mechanism for certifying
members of the community. The current system recognizes the
combination of talent and dedication in three levels: Apprentice,
Journeyer, and Master. All these levels are determined by peer
certification. These certificates are entered in individual records
from the <a href="person/">People</a> page. This document explains
what the levels mean, and guidelines for deciding what level of
certification to use. </p>

<p> Please feel free to certify all of the Ghostscript community
members you know who have accounts here, especially those without many
certificates to begin with. The trust metric used to evaluate the
certificates is most robust when the certificate graph is dense. </p>

<p> To certify someone, make sure you're logged in, then go to the
person's page and use the pulldown form. </p>

<p> The guidelines for levels shouldn't be taken too seriously. The
most important thing is that they seem to do a great job keeping the
spam and noise down to a minimum. For more information, including how
the certificates are evaluated, see the <a
href="http://www.advogato.org/certs.html">certification</a> page on
Advogato. </p>

<h2>Master</h2>

<p> A Master is someone who knows Ghostscript inside and out, and is
doing major development. One exception is L. Peter Deutsch, who is
hereby granted the title "Master for life", and who will retain the
status of Master of Ghostscript even after he enters his long-deserved
retirement, whenever that will be. </p>

<h2>Journeyer</h2>

<p> The contributions of Journeyers are essential to
Ghostscript. Anyone who maintains a driver, writes documentation, or
releases useful software that integrates with Ghostscript, is entitled
to Journeyer status. </p>

<h2>Apprentice</h2>

<p> An Apprentice is someone who has contributed in some way to
Ghostscript, but is still striving to learn more about
Ghostscript. People who are using Ghostscript in a creative way are
entitled to Apprentice status. </p>

</page>
